Thomas Foxen Anderson Papers 1928-1989 Mss.Ms.Coll.75
American Philosophical Society
- Series VI. Research Notes and Notebooks, 1931-1977; 6 boxes; 2.75 linear feet
  - "Osmotic Shock", 1949, 1952 (Box 48)
  - "Pedigrees"--Notebook, 1956-1957 (Box 49)
  - "Phage Meeting--Cold Spring Harbor", 1958 (Box 49)
  - "Photochemie"--Notebook, n.d. (Box 49)
  - [Physics Problems]--Notebook, n.d. (Box 49)
  - "Physikalisch Chemisches Praktikum"--Notebook, 1932 (Box 49)
  - "Preparation of Phage"--Notebook, 1959, 1961 (Box 49)
  - "Probability Calculus and Survival of T2 on Irradiated B" (Box 49)
  - "Le Problème des Quanta en Radiobiologie" by A. Lacassagne--Notes, n.d. (Box 49)
  - "Propositions: Crystal Structure", n.d. (Box 49)
  - "Resolution and Electron Density Notes" (Box 49)
  - "Results with Dropping Hg Electrode", 1943 (Box 49)
  - [Serial Sections]--Notebook, 1957-1965 (Box 49)
  - [Notes on Works about Electron Microscopy], n.d. (Box 49)
  - "Specimens"--Notebook, 1941-1958 (Box 49)
  - "Specimens in File"--Notebook, 1942-1945 (Box 49)
  - "The Sputtering of Metals by the Electron Beam", [194-] (Box 49)
  - Stereoscopic Measurements, n.d. (Box 49)
  - "Surface Chemistry"--Notebook, 1937 (Box 50)
  - "Surface Chemistry Data Sheets", 1937 (Box 50)
  - "Tryptophane Analysis and Deriv.", 1944-1945 (Box 50)
  - Unidentified, 18 Mar. 1959 (Box 50)
  - Unidentified, n.d.; 5 notebooks (Box 50)
- Series VII. Photographs, 1938-1988; 25 boxes; 19 linear feet
  Prints and negatives of electron micrographs that Anderson took of viruses and Drosophila, among other specimens. Some of the micrographs were used for articles, while others are unpublished. The prints are of varying sizes, including many oversized, and many are unidentified. There are also a few photographs of Anderson and his colleagues.
  - Aeromonas, 1966 (Box 51)
  - Ant, 1974 (Box 51)
  - Arber, Werner (Box 51)
    -See Ser.VII, "Les Genevois Vous Souhaitent une Bonne Année!"
  - "The Activation of the Bacterial Virus T4 by L-Tryptophan", [1948] (Box 51)
  - Aeromonas, 1966 (Box 51)
  - "Alpha-Phage", n.d. (Box 51)
  - Anderson, Thomas F. and Eduard Kellenberger (Box 51)
  - Anderson, Thomas F. in Groups of People, 1963, n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Astigmatism Tests", 1959-1960 (Box 51)
  - "B + T2", 1950 (Box 51)
  - "B x T4 + Anti T2", 1962 (Box 51)
  - "B x T4 Diluted + Anti T4", 1962 (Box 51)
  - "B + T4 + l-Trypt", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "B and T2 Phage", 1949 (Box 51)
  - B. Fusiformis, n.d. (Box 51)
  - "B Ghosts + T2r+", 1951 (Box 51)
  - "B. Megatherium", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "B. Subtilis and Antisheep Serum Mixed at 0.1 Dil. of Serum" (Box 51)
  - "B. Subtilis and Antisubtilis" (Box 51)
  - "B. Subtilis (Spores)", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "B2H6 (l) Microphotometer Tracings", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Bacterial Viruses - Structure and Function", [1959] (Box 51)
  - "Bacteriophage Anti-Coli PC", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Bacteriophage T4", 1960 (Box 51)
  - "Bacteriophages T2", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Bacteriophages T5", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Bacteriophages T7", n.d. (Box 51)
  - Brink, Marjorie and Frank Brink (Box 51)
  - Bronk, Detlev (Box 51)
    -See Ser.VII, Harthne[?], Kieffer, Betty Harthne[?], Detlev Bronk
  - Butterfly (Morpho Cypris) Wing Scale (Box 51)
  - "Cl. Botulinum", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "C-Phage", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "CsCL Run on P1 of 22(VII(60", 1960 (Box 51)
  - "CV3", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "CV4", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Calculation of Atomic Cross Sections in the Electron Microscope", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Carbon Replica of Spirillum", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Cell Wall of B", 1960 (Box 51)
    -See also Ser.II, "Cell Wall of B"--Sketch
  - "Coli Slant. 5 1/2h + ( Crude. Washed 10X", n.d. (Box 51)
  - Competent and Non-Competent Bacteria of Roger M. Herriott, [1966] (Box 51)
    -See also Ser.I, Herriott, Roger M., 27 May 1966
  - "Copper-Phthalocyanine Crystal", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Cross Section from Frog Skeletal Muscle by F.S. Sjöstrand and Ebba Anderssen", 1961-1964 (Box 51)
  - Cross Section of Type EMU Microscope, 1945 (Box 51)
  - "Diafine" (Box 51)
  - "Diatome Shells", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Diatoms", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Dietophone", n.d. (Box 51)
  - Diphtheria, n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Distilled H2O Control", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Dow Latex + Bacterium", n.d. (Box 51)
  - "Drosophila", 1975 (Box 51)
  - [Drosophila Electron Micrographs]. Folder #1, 1974-1977 (Box 51)
  - [Drosophila Electron Micrographs]. Folder #2, 1974-1977 (Box 51)
  - "E. Coli Lysing 23 Min. after Infection with T2 Phage", n.d. (Box 52)
  - "E. Coli Strain B", n.d. (Box 52)
  - "E. Coli Strain B and T2 Phage (Gold Shadowed)" (Box 52)
  - "E. Coli with Adsorbed T4 Phage", n.d. (Box 52)
  - E Typhosa, n.d. (Box 52)
  - "Eccentric Plaques", 1958 (Box 52)
  - "Effect of Host Cell Wall Material on the Adsorbability of Cofactor-Requiring T4", 1969 (Box 52)
  - [Electron Microscope Experiments], 1954-1955 (Box 52)
  - "The Electron Microscope in Medical Research", [1946] (Box 52)
  - "An Electron Microscope Study of the Digestion of E. Coli by Trypsin and Lysozyme", [1954] (Box 52)
  - "An Electron Microscopic Study of the Precipitin Reaction", [196-] (Box 52)
  - "Electron Microscopy of Microorganisms". Folder #1, 1953-1956 (Box 52)
  - "Electron Microscopy of Microorganisms". Folder #2, 1953-1956 (Box 52)
  - "Evaporated Gold", 5 Dec. 1956 (Box 52)
  - [Experiment Demonstrations], n.d. (Box 52)
  - "Fractionation of Shope Papilloma Virus in Cesium Chloride Density Gradients", 1962; 3 folders (Box 52)
  - "Fowl Coryza", n.d. (Box 52)
  - "Further Electron Microscope Studies on Arthropod Tracheae", [1942] (Box 52)
  - "Gamma-Phage", n.d. (Box 53)
  - "Les Genevois Vous Souhaitent une Bonne Année!", n.d. (Box 53)
    Arber, Werner
    Kellenberger, Grete
    Lark, Gordon
  - "Genomic Masking and Recombination between Serologically Unrelated Phages 22 and 221", 1961 (Box 53)
  - Greeting Cards, 1962, n.d. (Box 53)
  - Harthne[?], Kieffer, Betty Harthne[?], Detlev Bronk, n.d. (Box 53)
  - Heat Inactivated and Normal T5", [1951] (Box 53)
  - "Hemolyzed Human RBC", n.d. (Box 53)
  - "Hemolyzed Red Blood Cell", 1950 (Box 53)
  - Honey Bee Trachea (Box 53)
  - Icosadeltahedral Models for the First Nine Possible Triangulation Numbers, n.d. (Box 53)
  - "Identification of Poliovirus Particles of Different Antigenicity by Specific Agglutination as Seen in the Electron Microscope", 1961-1962 (Box 53)
  - "In Vitro Morphogenesis of Phage P22 from Heads and Base-Plate Parts", 1967 (Box 53)
  - "In Vitro Studies on the Gene 21 Dependent Proteolysis of Several Proteins Involved in the Head Morphogenesis of Bacteriophage T4", 1975 (Box 53)
  - "Influenza. Ether Washed Virus", n.d. (Box 53)
  - [Institute for Cancer Research?], n.d. (Box 53)
  - "An Instrument for Continuously Recording the Concentration of Nitrogen in Gas Mixtures", 1946 (Box 53)
  - "Jack Schultz, May 7, 1904 - April 29, 1971" (Box 53)
  - KA (Shigella Flexineri Type 5), 1955 (Box 53)
  - Kaolin, n.d. (Box 53)
  - Kelemen, Mary V., [1957] (Box 53)
  - Kellenberger, Eduard (Box 53)
    -See Ser.VII, Anderson Thomas F. and Eduard Kellenberger
  - Kellenberger, Grete (Box 53)
  - Laboratory Workers (Unidentified), n.d. (Box 53)
  - "Lambda Phage", 1960 (Box 53)
  - Lark, Gordon (Box 53)
  - Larrabee, Martin and Barbara Larrabee (Box 53)
  - "Lead Arsenate", n.d. (Box 53)
  - "Light Disintegrated Cotton Fibre", n.d. (Box 53)
  - Lilly, John C. (Box 53)
    -See Ser.VII, Pappenheimer, John and John C. Lilly
  - "Lime Carson", n.d. (Box 53)
  - Live Microorganisms (Electron Micrographs)--Laboratoire D'Optique Électronique du C.N.R.S. Toulouse, 1961 (Box 53)
  - "Log Etec", 1975 (Box 53)
  - "Lysis of B by T2", 1965 (Box 53)
  - "Mecurochrome", n.d. (Box 53)
  - "Meg. Sonic", n.d. (Box 53)
  - "A Method for Eliminating Gross Artefacts in Drying Specimens", 1950-1952 (Box 53)
  - "Microscopie Électronique sur Film en Couleurs Ektachrome Lumière du Jour", [1956] (Box 53)
  - "The Molecular Organization of Virus Particles", [1967] (Box 53)
  - "Morphological Structure of Rickettsiae", 1942-1943 (Box 53)
  - "Morphological Structure of the Virus of Vaccinia", 1942 (Box 53)
  - "Morphological Variants of Coliphage P1". Folder #1, [1970] (Box 53)
  - "Morphological Variants of Coliphage P1". Folder #2, [1970] (Box 53)
  - "Morphological Variants of the Bacteriophage P1", [1960] (Box 53)
  - "Morphologies of Bacteriophage Virions", 1971-1972 (Box 54)
  - "The Morphology and Osmotic Properties of Bacteriophage Systems", [1953] (Box 54)
  - "Moth Antenna", 1974 (Box 54)
  - "Moth. Section of Antenna" (Box 54)
  - "Muscle and Other Sections" (Box 54)
  - "Negative Staining and Its Use in the Study of Viruses and Their Serological Reactions", 1962 (Box 54)
  - "Nerve Sheath (Cat)", n.d. (Box 54)
  - "Nucleo-Cytoplasmic Relations in Salivary-Gland Cells of Drosophila", 1955 (Box 54)
  - "On the Fine Structures of the Temperate Bacteriophages P1, P2 and P22", 1960 (Box 54)
  - "On the Inheritability of Plasmids and the Population Dynamics of Cultured Cells", 1975 (Box 54)
  - "On the Structure and Osmotic Properties of Phage Particles", [1953] (Box 54)
  - "On the Structures of Various Bacteriophages", 1959-1961 (Box 54)
  - Optical Diffractogram of Phage Tail, 1965 (Box 54)
  - "P1", 1960; 5 folders (Box 54)
  - "P1 Phage", 1960 (Box 55)
  - "P1 Virulent", 1953 (Box 55)
  - "P2", 1960 (Box 55)
  - P22, 1965 (Box 55)
  - "P22--Alain Corcos" (Box 55)
  - "P22 Phage", 1960 (Box 55)
  - "P22 Plaques", n.d. (Box 55)
  - "P22t 15(XI(61(1,2,3,4", 1978 (Box 55)
  - "P221", 1960 (Box 55)
  - "P. Aurelia", 1963 (Box 55)
  - "PC Phage", n.d. (Box 55)
  - "PKS, a New RAF Related Sequence in Man", n.d. (Box 55)
  - Pappenheimer, John and John C. Lilly (Box 55)
  - "Paramecia", 1963-1964; 2 folders (Box 55)
  - "Paramecia". Folder #2, 1963-1964 (Box 55)
  - "Paramecium Caudatum", 1950 (Box 55)
  - [Phage by David Bradley, University of Edinburgh], n.d. (Box 55)
  - "Phase Contrast Electron Micrograph", 1953 (Box 55)
  - "Physical and Chemical Studies on Isolated Pellicles of Paramecium Aurelia", 1967 (Box 55)
  - Plectonema Boryanum, 1967 (Box 55)
  - Polio I, 1961 (Box 55)
  - "Polystyrene on Both Sides of C Film Replica of Red Cell", n.d. (Box 56)
  - "Potato Yellow Dwarf", n.d. (Box 56)
  - "The Preparation of Holey Films for Electron Microscopy", 1962 (Box 56)
  - "Preservation of Structure in Dried Specimens", Jul 1954 (Box 56)
  - "P[roteus] Vulgaris" (Box 56)
  - R17 (Crude Concentrate) (Box 56)
  - "The Raman Spectrum of Boron Trifluoride Gas", [1938] (Box 56)
  - "The Raman Spectrum of Liquid Diborane", [1938] (Box 56)
  - "Receptor Glycoprotein (from Human Urine) Attached to Particles of Influenza Virus"--M.E. Bayer (Box 56)
  - "Recombination: P22 and P221", 1961 (Box 56)
  - Rickettsial Bodies, n.d. (Box 56)
  - "S. Faecalis Membranes", 1959 (Box 56)
  - "Sacch. Cerevisiae", n.d. (Box 56)
  - "Sarcina-Like Organism", 1960 (Box 56)
  - Schultz, Jack, Spring 1971 (Box 56)
  - "Serial Sections for Electron Microscopy", 1954 (Box 56)
  - "Serial Sections of Smears for Electron Microscopy", 1955 (Box 56)
  - "Serial Sections of Whole Cell", n.d. (Box 56)
  - "Shope Papilloma", 1960 (Box 56)
  - "Some Fundamental Limitations to the Preservation of Three-Dimensional Specimens for the Electron Microscope", [1954] (Box 56)
  - "Specific Insertion and Deletion of IS1-Like DNA Element Causes the Reversible Expression of the Virulence (Vi) Capsular Antigen of Citrobacter Freundii in Escherichia Coli", 1988 (Box 56)
  - "The Spermatazoon and Fertilization Membrane of Arbacia Punctulata as Shown by the Electron Microscope", [1943] (Box 56)
  - "Spirilla", n.d. (Box 56)
  - "Spirocheta Microdentium", n.d. (Box 56)
  - Stereographic Sample, 1 Jul 1976 (Box 56)
  - "Stereographs (Unidentified), 1942-1950; 2 folders (Box 56)
  - "Stereoscopic Studies of Cells and Viruses in the Electron Microscope", [1952] (Box 56)
  - "Structural Abnormalities on the Surface of Epidermoid Carcinoma Cells", 1955 (Box 56)
  - "Structure and Genetic Properties of Bacterial Viruses", 1963 (Box 56)
  - "The Structure of Normal and Contracted Tail Sheaths of T4 Bacteriophage", 1966 (Box 56)
  - "Structure of Type 5 Adenovirus II. Fine Structure of Virus Subunits. Morphologic Relationship of Structural Subunits to Virus Specific Soluble Antigens from Infected Cells", 1963 (Box 56)
  - "The Structures of Certain Biological Specimens Prepared by the Critical Point Method", 1952 (Box 57)
  - "The Study of Colloids with the Electron Microscope", [1942] (Box 57)
  - "The Study of Viruses", n.d. (Box 57)
  - "Sur les Processus de Conjugaison et de Recombinaison chez Escherichia Coli. III. Aspects Morphologiques en Microscopie Électronique", [1957] (Box 57)
  - "The Surface Structure of Escherichia Coli", 1965 (Box 57)
  - "T2, T4, T6", 1959 (Box 57)
  - T2 and Anti-T2, 1962 (Box 57)
  - T2 and Anti-T4, 1962 (Box 57)
  - "T2 and E. Coli B" (Box 57)
  - "T2 and T4" (Box 57)
  - "T2 Bacteriophage Model", [1962] (Box 57)
  - "T2 Bacteriophage Particles", [1962] (Box 57)
  - T2 Bacteriophage Tail Fragments Negatively Stained with Neutralized Silicotungstate (Box 57)
  - "T2. Brenner and Horne's EMG's", 1959 (Box 57)
  - "T2 Dil + Anti T4", 1962 (Box 57)
  - "T2 Fiber Preparation", 1962 (Box 57)
  - "T2 Fibers and Sheaths after Digestion with Proteinase", 1962 (Box 57)
  - "T2. Kellenberger's Models", 1965 (Box 57)
  - "T2 Phage", n.d. (Box 57)
  - "T2 Sheath Preparation", 1962 (Box 57)
  - "T2r+", 1961 (Box 57)
  - "T2r+ and E. Coli B Ghosts" (Box 57)
  - "T3", 1967 (Box 57)
  - T3 and T7, 1945 (Box 57)
  - "T4", 1961 (Box 57)
  - T4, T5, T6, n.d. (Box 57)
  - "T4 after Treatment with Acid and DNAase", 1962 (Box 57)
  - T4 and Anti-T2, 1962 (Box 57)
  - T4 and Anti-T4, 1962 (Box 57)
  - "T4 + Horse Anti T4". Folder #1, 1974-1980 (Box 57)
  - "T4 + Horse Anti T4". Folder #2, 1974-1980 (Box 57)
  - "T4 and PTA and Sucrose" (Box 57)
  - T4 and Pyridylalanine, 1945 (Box 57)
  - "T4 Fibers and Sheaths" (Box 57)
  - "T4 Maaløe", 1961 (Box 57)
  - "T4 on B", n.d. (Box 58)
  - "T4 on Collodion", n.d. (Box 58)
  - "T4 Phage", n.d. (Box 58)
  - T4 Plaques, 17 Oct. 1947 (Box 58)
  - "T5", 1960 (Box 58)
  - "T5 and Citrate (Heated)", 1951 (Box 58)
  - "T5 on B" (Box 58)
  - "T5 Phage", 1959-1960 (Box 58)
  - T6, 1958 (Box 58)
  - "T6 Phage", 1963 (Box 58)
  - "T-Even Adsorption Drawings" (Box 58)
  - T-Even Heads, 1971 (Box 58)
  - "T. Microdentium", n.d. (Box 58)
  - "T. Pallidum", n.d. (Box 58)
  - "Techniques for the Preservation of Three-Dimensional Structure in Preparing Specimens for the Electron Microscope", [1951] (Box 58)
  - "Textile Fibre", 19654 (Box 58)
  - "Thiobacillus Macroflagellum", n.d. (Box 58)
  - "Thiobacillus Thioxidans", n.d. (Box 58)
  - "Tobacco Mosaic Virus" #1, n.d. (Box 58)
  - T[obacco] M[osaic] V[irus] #2, n.d. (Box 58)
  - T[obacco] M[osaic] V[irus] + ABS, n.d. (Box 58)
  - T[obacco] M[osaic] V[irus] + ATMV + BS, n.d. (Box 58)
  - "Tobacco Mosaic Virus. Gel", n.d. (Box 58)
  - "Tremolite Talc", n.d. (Box 58)
  - "Trichocysts in Paramecium: A Method of Isolation and Observations on Fine Structure", [1964] (Box 58)
  - "Truog", n.d. (Box 58)
  - "Typhoid and Antityphoid" (Box 58)
  - "Typhus", n.d. (Box 58)
  - Unidentified, 1941-1960; 1962-1977; 7 folders (Box 58)
  - "The Use of Critical Point Phenomena in Preparing Specimens for the Electron Microscope", 1950 (Box 59)
  - "Vibrio Schuylkilliensis", n.d. (Box 59)
  - "R.C. Williams. Pictures of Air-Dried and Frozen Dried Influenza A Virus", 10 Sep. 1954 (Box 59)
  - Wolpers, Carl--"Elektronenmikroskopische Untersuchungen der Innenstrukturen Kernloser Erythrocyten", [1955] (Box 59)
  - Woods Hole Electron Micrographs (Contact Prints), n.d. (Box 59)
  - Glass Negatives, Jun.-Jul. 1959 (Box 60)
  - Glass Negatives, Oct.-Nov. 1959 (Box 61)
  - Glass Negatives, Nov.-Dec. 1959 (Box 62)
  - Glass Negatives, Jan.-Mar. 1960 (Box 63)
  - Glass Negatives, Mar. 1960 (Box 64)
  - Glass Negatives, Mar. 1960 (Box 65)
  - Glass and film negatives, 1974-1977, n.d. (Box 66)
  - Glass positives, 1949-1951 (Box 67)
  - Glass and film positives, 1951-1958, 1965, n.d. (Box 68)
  - Lantern slides, n.d. (Box 69)
  - Lantern slides, n.d. (Box 70)
  - Lantern slides, n.d. (Box 71)
  - Lantern slides, n.d. (Box 72)
  - Stereoscopic slides, 1950s (Box 73)
  - Stereoscopic Slides and Slide Viewer, 1950s (Box 74)
  - 35mm Slides, 1960s (Box 75)